<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Miscellaneous on Daoyin Chuan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/misc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Miscellaneous on Daoyin Chuan</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 11:42:25 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/misc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Baduanjin</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/misc/baduanjin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 11:42:25 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/misc/baduanjin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Baduan literally means “eight sections” and jin, “brocade”.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Like most popular traditions in any culture the origins of Baduanjin are shrouded in myth and legend. Some say they began several thousands of years ago. There are, in fact, historical records of exercises that resemble Baduanjin dating back 4000 years to the time of the Yao settlements. An exciting piece of evidence was unearthed in the late 1970’s known as the Dao Ying Xing Qi Fa (Method of Inducing Free Flow of Chi). This silk book dates from the Western Han Dynasty and contains 44 drawings of men and women from different social classes in exercise postures very similar to Baduanjin.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taiji Ruler</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/misc/taijichih/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 11:42:25 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/misc/taijichih/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Taiji Chih or Ruler (no relationship with Taijiquan) is a sacred and secret qigong first made public in 1954 by Master Zhao Zhong-dao. It is called the Ruler (Chi, sometimes spelled Chih) because during the basic exercise the hands are held about a foot apart. You may practice this qigong while holding a foot-long “Ruler” between the palms. The Ruler is made of a light porous wood such as willow and rounded at both ends so it fits comfortably in the hands. The physical ruler encourages the flow of ch’i. The Taiji Chih system consists of gentle rocking and swaying movements that build ch’i in the feet, the dantian, and the hands. It can be used for self-healing or as a preparation for any form of massage therapy or therapeutic touch. Your hands will feel warm, vibrating, full of healing power after a few minutes’ practice. In the United States, several bizarre variations to the Ruler have become popular, many with little relationship to Zhao’s original techniques. The method we present here at Daoyin Chuan has been handed down from direct students of Zhao, several second- or third generation students, and then corroborated by comparison with Zhao’s original Chinese text.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yijinjing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/misc/yijinjing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 11:42:25 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/misc/yijinjing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;DaMo or Bodhidharma, an Indian holy man, came to China where he came upon the Shaolin Temple. While there he noticed the deplorable state of health the monks had. DaMo then went into seclusion into a natural rock cave for nine years. During that time he invented a form of ch’i-kung called Yijinjing (meaning “Muscle/Tendon Transformation”). And though DaMo certainly must have drawn upon his Indian yoga techniques in inventing Yijinjing, what he actually did was combine his own internal kung fu theory to the already existing Chinese theory of qigong, while taking the differences in Chinese physiology and physical environment into account. Chinese ch’i-kung was actually invented independently approximately 3,000 years ago, curiously enough also by a religious leader, Lao Tze, the founder of Taoism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wuji Qigong</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/misc/wuji/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 11:42:25 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/misc/wuji/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A very simple and effective approach to meditation is called Wuji Qigong in Chinese. Its core is standing meditation. Loosely translated, “Qigong” means “energy work” and “wuji” means “void” or “emptiness.” The two pillars of this practice are to still the mind and the body. Once we are into the silence of the mind, the void or empty mind, we begin to sense the natural state of our being.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wuji Qigong may be practiced while either sitting or standing. In either position, the three harmonies are an essential part of this practice. The three harmonies are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
