<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Daoyin Chuan</title>
    <link>https://daoyinchuan.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Daoyin Chuan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://daoyinchuan.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About Us</title>
      <link>https://daoyinchuan.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 11:42:25 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daoyinchuan.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>About Us Just as the rosebud contains within it the innate form of the perfect flower, so do we all contain within ourselves the innate form of our own perfection. Under the proper conditions of sun, water and nutrients, the bud unfolds to reveal the rose. Likewise the simple conditions of the practice helps us break through a lifetime of old habits and programmed patterns of posture and movement, allowing what is essential in us – physically, mentally and spiritually – to naturally unfold.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Practice</title>
      <link>https://daoyinchuan.github.io/practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 11:42:25 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daoyinchuan.github.io/practice/</guid>
      <description>Our Practice These three internal arts create a triad of our practice:
Qigong Baduanjin Yijinjing Taiji Chih (Ruler) Wuji Qigong (Cai Songfang) Yiquan Wang Xiangzhai (1885-1963) Han Xingyuan (1915-1983) Fong Ha (1937-2019) Taijiquan Yang Family Style Dong Yingjie (1897-1961) Yang Zhenming (1910-1985) Fong Ha (1937-2019) Tui Shou – Fixed and Moving Da Lu – Big Rollback Dao - Sabre Ch&amp;rsquo;i Kung (qigong) practice is expressed in four fundamental disciplines: sitting mediation; Wu Chi Chi Kung (Wuji Qigong), or &amp;ldquo;standing mediation;&amp;rdquo; I Ch&amp;rsquo;uan (yiquan), or &amp;ldquo;intention practice;&amp;rdquo; and Tai Chi Ch&amp;rsquo;uan (taijiquan).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sifu Fong Ha</title>
      <link>https://daoyinchuan.github.io/fongha/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 11:42:25 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daoyinchuan.github.io/fongha/</guid>
      <description>Sifu Fong Ha has been practicing Chinese internal arts since his childhood and has studied with many renowned teachers. He began his studies of Yang-style Taijiquan in 1953 with Tung Ying-chieh, and continued with Yang Sau-chung, the eldest son of Yang Cheng-fu. Fong&amp;rsquo;s exploration then led into the realm of I Ch&amp;rsquo;uan. One of the few I Ch&amp;rsquo;uan teachers in the West, Fong Ha is well known for his power, graciousness, and cosmopolitan charm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Students</title>
      <link>https://daoyinchuan.github.io/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 11:42:25 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daoyinchuan.github.io/links/</guid>
      <description>Sifu Fong Ha&amp;rsquo;s Students Jan Diepersloot (Walnut Creek, CA) Michael Mayer (San Francisco, CA) Marek Wajsman (Jersusalem, Israel) The Effortless Way (Spokane, WA) Links Sifu Fong Ha (Berkley, CA) Fong Ha’s Yiquan: More than a martial art, Part 1 Fong Ha’s Yiquan: More than a martial art, Part 2 Video Links Master Fong Ha - on Yiquan Grandmaster Fong Ha in Israel 1995 Grandmaster Fong Ha in Israel Grandmaster Fong Ha about balance Tu&amp;rsquo;i Shou With Sifu Fong Ha Greece 2006 Tai Chi and Qigong Retreat with Sifu Fong Ha Israel 2010 The essence of practice - Sifu Fong Ha </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
